Guide to the Fredericka Martin Papers ALBA.001
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series II: Medical Subject Files, 1937-1987
  - Medical Sites: Autochirs, undated, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Medical Sites: Barcelona, undated, 1938-1943, 1968-1972 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Medical Sites: Barcelona: Vallarca, undated, 1938, 1970-1971 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Medical Sites: Belalcázar, undated, 1937-1938, 1968-1970 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Medical Sites: Belchite, undated, 1937-1938, 1972-1975 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Medical Sites: Benicasim, undated, 1937-1938, 1970- 1977 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Medical Sites: Benicasim: Komensky Hospital, One Year at Wartime Hospital in Democratic Spain(photocopy of Czech publication), undated (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Medical Sites: Benisa, undated, 1938-1939, 1971-1972 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Medical Sites: Bisbal de Falset, undated (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Medical Sites: Brunete Front, undated (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Medical Sites: Cambrils, undated (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Medical Sites: Caspe, Casa Jimineta, undated, 1938 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Medical Sites: Castillejo, undated, 1937-1939, 1969-1971 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Medical Sites: Castillejo: Transfer Order for Wounded Soldier (document in Spanish), Jul 1937 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Medical Sites: Catalonia, undated, 1938-1938, 1970-1982 (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Medical Sites: Cedrillos, undated (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Medical Sites: Colmenar de Oreja, undated, 1971, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Medical Sites: Córdoba, undated, 1937-1938, 1969-1975 (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Medical Sites: Córdoba: Clippings, undated, 1938 (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Medical Sites: Cuenca, undated, 1937-1938, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Medical Sites: Cuenca: Cirac Esropañá, S.: Martirologio de Cuena(excerpt), 1947 (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - Medical Sites: Cueva de la Patita, undated, 1937, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - Medical Sites: Cuevas Labradas, undated, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Medical Sites: Denia, undated, 1938, 1943-1973 (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - Medical Sites: Ebro, undated, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 37)
  - Medical Sites: El Escorial, undated, 1970-1971 (Box 15, Folder 38)
  - Medical Sites: Evacuation, undated, 1970-1971 (Box 15, Folder 39)
  - Medical Sites: Fuencarral, undated, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 40)
  - Medical Sites: General, undated, 1936-1938, 1970-1979 (Box 15, Folder 41)
  - Medical Sites: Godella, undated (Box 15, Folder 42)
  - Medical Sites: Grañen, undated, 1936, 1971-1972 (Box 15, Folder 43)
  - Medical Sites: La Granja, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Medical Sites: Hijar de Puebla, undated, 1969-1970 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Medical Sites: Huete, undated, 1937-1938, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Medical Sites: Jarama, undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Medical Sites: Las Planas, undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Medical Sites: Madrid, undated, 1937-1938, 1943-1980 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Medical Sites: Mahora, undated, 1938, 1981-1982 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Medical Sites: Marsa, undated (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Medical Sites: Mataró, undated, 1938, 1970-1979 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Medical Sites: Mezquita, undated, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Medical Sites: Morata Front, undated, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Medical Sites: Moya, undated, 1938 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Medical Sites: Murcia, undated (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Medical Sites: Murcia, 1937-1938 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Medical Sites: Murcia, 1970-1978 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Medical Sites: Murcia: Children's Home, undated, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Medical Sites: Murcia: General Lukaz Children's Home Financial Report, Oct 1937-Feb 1938 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Medical Sites: Onteniente, undated, 1937-1938, 1970-1976 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Medical Sites: Orihuela, undated, 1970-1972, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Medical Sites: El Paraíso Hospital, undated, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Medical Sites: Pontonas, undated (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Medical Sites: Pozoblanco, undated, 1969 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Medical Sites: La Puebla del Valverde, undated, 1938 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Medical Sites: Quinto, undated, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Medical Sites: Reus, undated, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Medical Sites: Romeral, undated, 1937, 1970-1971 (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - Medical Sites: Sabadell, undated (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - Medical Sites: Saelices, undated (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - Medical Sites: S'Agaro, undated, 1970-1971, 1975 (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - Medical Sites: San Clemente, undated (Box 16, Folder 30)
  - Medical Sites: Santa Coloma de Queralt, undated (Box 16, Folder 31)
  - Medical Sites: Seguro de Los Baños, undated, 1939, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 32)
  - Medical Sites: Tarancon, undated, 1937-1938, 1949-1979 (Box 16, Folder 33)
  - Medical Sites: Tarancon: Bombing, undated, 1938, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 34)
  - Medical Sites: Tarragona, undated, 1939, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 35)
  - Medical Sites: Teruel Front (including Alfambra), undated, 1937-1938, 1969-1975 (Box 16, Folder 36)
  - Medical Sites: Thirty Fifth Division Hospital, undated, 1937, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 37)
  - Medical Sites: Torrelodones, undated, 1937, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 38)
  - Medical Sites: Tortosa, undated, 1939 (Box 16, Folder 39)
  - Medical Sites: Ucles, undated (Box 16, Folder 40)
  - Medical Sites: Valdeganga, undated, 1937-1938, 1968-1976 (Box 16, Folder 41)
  - Medical Sites: Valencia, undated, 1937-1938, 1968-1971 (Box 16, Folder 42)
  - Medical Sites: Vallivaña, undated, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 43)
  - Medical Sites: Valls, undated, 1938, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 44)
  - Medical Sites: Valsequillo, undated, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 45)
  - Medical Sites: Vich, undated, 1938, 1970-1979 (Box 16, Folder 46)
  - Medical Sites: Villa Nueva de la Jara, undated, 1970-1971 (Box 16, Folder 47)
  - Medical Sites: Villa Paz, undated, 1937-1939, 1968-1980 (Box 16, Folder 48)
  - Medical Sites: Villa Paz: Children's Colony, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 49)
  - Medical Sites: Villa Paz: Christmas, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 50)
  - Medical Sites: Villa Paz: Evacuation, undated, 1970-1972 (Box 16, Folder 51)
  - Medical Sites: Villa Paz: Medical Records and Documents, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 52)
  - Medical Sites: Villa Paz: Personnel, undated, 1937-1938, 1970-1972 (Box 16, Folder 53)
  - Medical Sites: Villarejo, undated (Box 16, Folder 54)
  - Medical Sites: Villarobledo, undated (Box 16, Folder 55)
  - Medical Unit: Diagram of Sanitary Service Structure (Hand-drawn), ca.1937 (Box 16, Folder 56)
  - Medical Units by Group, undated, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 57)
  - Passport Issues, 1937, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 58)
  - Red Cross: American: Research Photocopies, Correspondence and Notes, undated, 1936-1937, 1950-1977 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Red Cross: American and International: Correspondence (Photocopies), 1936-1938 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Red Cross: International: Notes, ca.1977 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Red Cross: International: Committee Reports and Conferences (Photocopies), undated, 1936-1939, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Red Cross: Spanish (Cruz Roja Espanola), undated, 1936-1939, 1969-1972 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Shapiro, Martin F.: "Medical Aid to the Spanish Republic During the Spanish Civil War", 1982 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Socorro Rojo Internacional: Miscellaneous Notes, undated, 1937, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Treatment: Blood Transfusion, undated, 1937-1939 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Treatment: General, undated, 1937-1938, 1970-1976 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Treatment: Malaria, undated, 1938-1941 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Treatment: Open Wound Fractures: Dr. Hiram Winnett Orr, 1923-1976 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Treatment: Open Wound Fractures: Dr. Hiram Winnett Orr, 1923-1976 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Treatment: Psychiatric Cases, undated, 1938-1941, 1969-1976 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Treatment: Surgery, undated, 1939, 1975 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Treatment: Wounds, undated, 1938-1940, 1969-1979 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Uniforms, undated, 1973-1975 (Box 17, Folder 16)
- Series III: Combat Personnel: Biographical Files and Correspondence, 1937-1987
  Series III. Combat Volunteers: Biographical Files and Correspondence, 1937-1985. This series includes correspondence from and biographical material on Spanish Civil War combat volunteers. Although Martin corresponded with volunteers from many countries, the majority of these files document United States volunteers. Like the medical personnel files, these files include accounts of activities in Spain and chronicle the lives of the veterans in their later years. The correspondence and other material here also document the fraternal nature of the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB), which provided financial, medical and legal assistance to its members. An example of this can be found in Robert Raven's file, which includes leaflets and a 1937 fundraising appeal on Robert Raven Rehabilitation Committee letterhead requesting aid for Raven who was blinded in Spain. Also notable is VALB correspondence related to the deportation of Carlos Soule Echeveria, a Spanish national who fought with the Abraham Lincoln Brigade. (Additional material on veterans and VALB can be found in Series V: General Subject Files).
  Among the veterans Martin corresponded with regularly were Edward Lending, David Miller, Steve Nelson, Mark Rauschwald, Irving Weissman and Randall (Pete) Smith, who headed up the veteran's Spanish Civil War Historical Committee. Other correspondents include VALB executive secretary Moe Fishman, Canadian volunteer William Beeching, and author Arthur Landis, with whom Martin had a heated exchange over the publication of his book. Recurring topics include Martin's concerns over finding a suitable repository for the Medical Bureau materials, consideration of whether the veterans should assume stewardship of their papers, and the establishment of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives at Brandeis.
  - Ayers, Frank (England), undated, 1938-1959 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Ayers, Frank (England), 1960-1970 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Ayers, Frank and Anita (England), 1971 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Ayers, Frank (England), 1972 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Ayers, Frank and Anita (England) from FM, 1971-1972 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Ayers, Frank and Anita (England), 1973 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Ayers, Frank (England), 1974 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Ayers, Frank (England), 1975 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Ayers, Frank (England), 1976 (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Ayers, Frank (England), 1977 (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Ayers, Frank (England) pt. 1, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - Ayers, Frank (England) pt. 2, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 28)
  - Ayers, Frank (England) pt. 1, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - Ayers, Frank (England) pt. 2, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 30)
  - Ayers, Frank (England), 1980 (Box 17, Folder 31)
  - Ayers, Frank (England), 1981 (Box 17, Folder 32)
  - Ayers, Frank (England), 1983 (Box 17, Folder 33)
  - Ayers, Frank and Anita (England), from FM, 1965; 1970 (Box 17, Folder 34)
  - Ayers, Frank and Anita (England), from FM, 1971-1973 (Box 17, Folder 35)
  - Ayers, Frank (England), from FM, 1978-1981 (Box 17, Folder 36)
  - Ayers, Frank and Anita (England), Holiday Cards, undated, 1952-1978 (Box 17, Folder 37)
  - Ayers, Frank (England), Draft Memoir, undated (Box 17, Folder 38)
  - Ayers, Frank (England), Reminiscences and Related Notes, undated, 1973-1976 (Box 17, Folder 39)
  - Ayers, Frank (England), to Toby Jensky, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 40)
  - Bailey, Thomas (Canada), 1970-1981 (Box 17, Folder 41)
  - Bard, Philip, undated (Box 17, Folder 42)
  - Beeching, William C. (Canada), 1979-1987 (Box 17, Folder 43)
  - Benson, William (Bill) (England), undated, 1938-1961 (Box 17, Folder 44)
  - Bessie, Alvah, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 45)
  - DeMaio, Anthony, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 46)
  - Doran, David, 1971 (Box 17, Folder 47)
  - Ehrenberg, Myron (Mike), undated, 1938, 1958-1974 (Box 17, Folder 48)
  - Fahy, Jack Bradley, undated (Box 17, Folder 49)
  - Felson, Milton, 1970-1979 (Box 17, Folder 50)
  - Fishman, Moe, undated, 1950-1953 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Fishman, Moe, 1954 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Fishman, Moe, 1955 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Fishman, Moe, 1956 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Fishman, Moe, 1957 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Fishman, Moe, 1958-1960 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Fishman, Moe, 1961-1964 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Fishman, Moe, 1965-1967 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Fishman, Moe, 1968-1969 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Fishman, Moe, 1970-1972 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Fishman, Moe, 1977-1978 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Fishman, Moe, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Fishman, Moe, 1981-1984 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Fishman, Moe from FM, undated, 1966 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Fishman, Moe from FM, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Fishman, Moe from FM (not sent), 1967 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Fishman, Moe from FM, 1968-1970 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Fishman, Moe from FM, 1972 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Fishman, Moe from FM, 1979, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Fishman, Moe from FM (draft and unsent), 1984-1985 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Fishman, Moe: Notes on, Money Orders, undated, 1967-1968 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Fishman, Moe to Cedric Belfrage, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Fishman, Moe to Tobyanne Martin, 1954 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Frank, Low, undated (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Frankel, Irving, undated, 1979-1981 (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Franklin, Zalmond, undated (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Freeman, Maurice, 1939 (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Gandall, William (Bill), 1954, 1970-1971 (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Gates, John, 1970-1970 (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Gayle, Louis A., 1969, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - Geiser, Carl Frederick, 1978-1987 (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - Giler, Henry, 1971-1977 (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - Goddard, Howard Owen, 1936 (Box 18, Folder 33)
  - Goldring, Benjamin, undated, 1977-1982 (Box 18, Folder 34)
  - Gordon, Dave, undated, 1967-1973, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 35)
  - Gordon, Louis, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 36)
  - Gottlieb, Albert (Al Stone), undated, 1970, 1979-1980 (Box 18, Folder 37)
  - Groden, Daniel Samuel, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 38)
  - Gross, Nat, 1956 (Box 18, Folder 39)
  - Grumet, Martin Johnson, undated, 1975-1979 (Box 18, Folder 40)
  - Gurney, Jason Patrick (England), undated, 1949, 1977-1984 (Box 18, Folder 41)
  - Halonen, Oiva and Tini, undated, 1972-1976 (Box 18, Folder 42)
  - Harriman, Manny, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 43)
  - Harris, Aaron and Helen, 1970-1982 (Box 18, Folder 44)
  - Harris, Abe (Albert Lyonel), undated, 1937, 1971-1974 (Box 18, Folder 45)
  - Harris, Sydney, 1971, 1976, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 46)
  - Haywood, Harry, undated, 1968-1983 (Box 18, Folder 47)
  - Heisler, Gus, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 48)
  - Hille, August Korpl, 1950-1952 (Box 18, Folder 49)
  - Hiss, Rudolph (Germany), undated (Box 18, Folder 50)
  - Holtzman, Benjamin, undated, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 51)
  - Honeycomb, John, 1938 (Box 18, Folder 52)
  - Hooker, Howard, undated (Box 18, Folder 53)
  - Hourihan, Martin William, undated, 1970-1971 (Box 18, Folder 54)
  - Hunter, Oscar Henry, 1937-1939, 1971-1980 (Box 18, Folder 55)
  - Hyde, Mark and Gertrude, 1943-1952 (Box 18, Folder 56)
  - Iceland, Benjamin Isaac, 1982-1985 (Box 18, Folder 57)
  - Juck, Joseph (Hungary), undated, 1982-1983 (Box 18, Folder 58)
  - Kailin, Clarence, undated, 1977-1981 (Box 18, Folder 59)
  - Kaiser, Herman (Sweden), 1938, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 60)
  - Karmen, Roman (Soviet Union), undated, 1973-1938 (Box 18, Folder 61)
  - Kaufman, Rubin, 1980 (Box 18, Folder 62)
  - Keen, Harry (including correspondence with brother, Arnold), 1937-1938, 1941-1946, 1975-1977 (Box 18, Folder 63)
  - Keith, Charles, 1973-1978 (Box 18, Folder 64)
  - Keller, Ford, 1938 (Box 18, Folder 65)
  - Klonsky, Bob and Helen, undated, 1966-1971 (Box 18, Folder 66)
  - Kozar, John, undated, 1942, 1978-1981 (Box 18, Folder 67)
  - Kranes, Lou, undated, 1937, 1967-1970 (Box 18, Folder 68)
  - Krieger, Sam, 1975-1976 (Box 18, Folder 69)
  - Lancer, Emanuel, undated, 1970-1971 (Box 18, Folder 70)
  - Landis, Arthur, undated, 1966-1978 (Box 18, Folder 71)
  - Lardner, James Philips, 1971, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 72)
  - Leider, Ben, undated, 1937 (Box 18, Folder 73)
  - Lending, Edward (Isaac), undated, 1961-1986 (Box 18, Folder 74)
  - Levine (Lane), Benjamin, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Linick, Edgar (German), undated, 1969, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Love, Vaughn Costine, undated, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Lucid, John Michael, undated, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - McDaniels, Eluard Luchell, undated, 1971 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - McNeil, Allan (a.k.a. Allan Johnson), 1939, 1966 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Mallan, Lloyd, 1939 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Margolis, Irving, undated (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Markowitz, Leo, 1972 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Martin (Detsinyi), David (Hungary/Australia), 1964-1968 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Martinez, John, 1977-1978 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Mates, Dave, 1972-1974 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Merriman, Robert and Marion, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Mickenberg, Morris, 1970 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Miletneaunu, Jonel (Romania), undated, 1969-1982 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Miller, David, undated, 1938, 1974-1982 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Miller, William Colfax, undated, 1974-1982 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Muller, John Philip, undated, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Murra, John V., 1950 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Nancarrow, Conlon Samuel, undated, 1977-1979 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Nance, Youngblood, undated, 1969-1973 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Nelson, Steve, undated, 1967-1972 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Nelson, Steve, 1973-1984 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Nesterenko, I. N. (Soviet Union), undated, 1969-1977 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - O'Flaherty, Charles, undated, 1978-1983 (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Oliva Campillo, Juan (Spain), undated, 1938, 1969-1982 (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Osheroff, Abraham, undated, 1979-1984 (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Owens, Blaine, undated, 1944 (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Owens, Harry F., 1975 (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - Peck, Samuel, undated, 1937, 1970-1982 (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - Perlman, (Norman and) Polly, 1974-1976 (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - Prago, Albert, undated, 1981-1982 (Box 19, Folder 32)
  - Rauschwald, Mark, undated, 1964-1978 (Box 19, Folder 33)
  - Raven, Robert, undated, 1937-1951, 1970 (Box 19, Folder 34)
  - Reed, Robert Lee, undated (Box 19, Folder 35)
  - Robbins, Albert, undated, 1971-1976 (Box 19, Folder 36)
  - Robel, Edward, 1938 (Box 19, Folder 37)
  - Robels, Gilberto Rojo, 1963-1971 (Box 19, Folder 38)
  - Rody, John, 1971-1976 (Box 19, Folder 39)
  - Rolfe, Eddie, undated, 1970 (Box 19, Folder 40)
  - Romero, Ernest J., 1982 (Box 19, Folder 41)
  - Rosenstein, Herman (a.k.a. Herman Gabby Klein) and Mildred, 1972-1984 (Box 19, Folder 42)
  - Rosner, Hyman, undated, 1969-1983 (Box 19, Folder 43)
  - Ross, Adolph (Buster) and Lillian, 1969 (Box 19, Folder 44)
  - Rubin, Henry (combat vet and lab technician), undated, 1970-1972 (Box 19, Folder 45)
  - Ryan (Swan), Williams G., undated, 1975-1979 (Box 19, Folder 46)
  - Sanborn, Blackie, undated (Box 19, Folder 47)
  - Schafran, Jack, undated, 1951-1971 (Box 19, Folder 48)
  - Schiff, Sam, 1971 (Box 19, Folder 49)
  - Schneider, Ted, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 50)
  - Schofs, Frederick (Germany), 1968-1984 (Box 19, Folder 51)
  - Schuetrum, Walter J., undated, 1938, 1970-1979 (Box 19, Folder 52)
  - Schulman, Jack, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 53)
  - Shapiro, Saul Meyer, undated, 1978-1985 (Box 19, Folder 54)
  - Shipman, Evan, undated, 1957, 1972-1976 (Box 19, Folder 55)
  - Siegel, Joseph, undated, 1970 (Box 19, Folder 56)
  - Sims, John, 1970 (Box 19, Folder 57)
  - Siqueiros, David A., undated, 1971-1980 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Smith, Clive (England), undated, 1977-1979 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Smith, Randall (Pete), undated, 1968-1979 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Smith, Randall (Pete), 1980-1983 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Soule Echeveria, Carlos (Spain): Deportation, undated, 1949-1954 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Stamm, Morris and Eleanor, 1975-1984 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Stanley, Fred O., 1985 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Steck, Bob, undated, 1979-1980 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Strauss, Sam and Rose, 1976 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Stuart, Yale, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Susman, William and Helen, undated, 1977-1985 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Thayer, Donald, undated, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Thompson, Robert, 1965 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Tisa, John, 1971-1982 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Titus, William, 1938 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Valenzuela, Manuel: Includes letters from Spain (photocopies), 1937, 1980 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Van der Schelling, Bart and Edna, undated, 1941, 1954-1978 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Villanueva, Nicolas Ramirez, undated, 1956, 1969-1981 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Voros, Sandor, 1937, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Wallach, Hy, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Weber, Franz (Germany), 1937-1940 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Weber, Franz (Germany), 1947-1952 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Weir, Harry Oscar, 1938 (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Weissman, Irving, undated, 1964 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Weissman, Irving, undated, 1965-1967 (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Weissman, Irving, 1968-1984 (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - Wellman, Saul, undated, 1970-1985 (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - Wellnitz, Fritz (Germany), undated, 1970-1974 (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - Wesson, Neil, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 28A)
  - Wheeler, Bill, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 28B)
  - Wolff, Milton, undated, 1945, 1970-1985 (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - Wolff, Paul, undated, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 30)
  - Yates, James, 1978-1982 (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - Yates, James Oscar (England), undated, 1982-1983 (Box 20, Folder 32)
- Series IV: General Correspondence, 1937-1985
  Series IV. General Correspondence, 1937-1985. This series consists of Martin's incoming and outgoing correspondence from a range of friends, political figures, researchers and former Medical Bureau officers and organizers. Included in this latter category are Executive Secretary Herman F. Reissig, Evelyn Ahrend Kirkpatrick, James Loeb, Louis Miller, Harold L. Oram, Violet Robbin, John Sherman, and Charles Tobach who contribute information on the structure and activities of the Medical Bureau in the United States. Other correspondents include: Canadian Communist leader Tim Buck and his wife Bess, journalist Herbert Matthews, writer Joesph North and his wife Helen, and Gina Medem, author of a book on Jewish participation in the Spanish Civil War. Also included is correspondence from historians Gabriel Jackson, Peter Wyden, Robert Rosenstone and Herbert Southworth. Of special note is a 1945 letter Martin sent to Congressional Chair of the Committee on Foreign Affairs Sol Bloom protesting U.S. relations with Franco. Also included in this series are several of Martin's address books (with loose notes and lists of addresses) and a number of business cards of contacts and friends in many countries.
  - Ahrend Kirkpatrick, Evelyn, undated, 1937-1938, 1972-1981 (Box 20, Folder 33)
  - Aparicion, Maite, undated, 1972-1983 (Box 20, Folder 34)
  - Aronson, James, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 35)
  - Ayers, Dais re: Frank Ayers, 1938 (Box 20, Folder 36)
  - Baldwin, Roger, 1971-1974 (Box 20, Folder 37)
  - Belfrage, Cedric, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 38)
  - Berenberg, Samuel, 1945 (Box 20, Folder 39)
  - Berman Schweitzer, Rose, 1953, 1981 (Box 20, Folder 40)
  - Bloom, Sol, 1945 (Box 20, Folder 41)
  - Bogin, Magda (with translations of poems by Maria Tercera Sinfonia), undated, 1968-1982 (Box 20, Folder 42)
  - Brie, Dorrit, undated, 1978-1982 (Box 20, Folder 43)
  - Buck, Tim and Bess, 1972-1981 (Box 20, Folder 44)
  - Carse, Robert, 1969-1970 (Box 20, Folder 45)
  - Cashman, Brian and Diane, undated, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 46)
  - Chubieco Alvarez, Pedro, 1974-1977 (Box 20, Folder 47)
  - Escobar, Pilar, 1957-1972 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Escudero, Isabel, 1975-1982 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Fles, Barthold, 1976 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Gago, Valeriano, undated, 1974-1980 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Gallego, Dolores, 1974 (Box 21, Folder 5)